Brian Isaboke Nyamumbe

Information Technology Specialist

22/12/1997

≥ nyamumbebrian157@gmail.com

+254727903007 • Nairobi, Kenya

in linkedin.com/in/brian-nyamumbe

★ https://brianprofile.netlify.app/

Profile

I am a passionate IT support specialist and a web developer with 1 year experience as an IT specialist. Having great skills in full stack web development; JavaScript, Node.js, React, among other skills, I aspire to work with developers and clients to make organizations reach their peak in technology.

Having in-depth understanding of diverse computer systems and networks, I am excellent in the technical aspects of IT technology thus providing support to users and making me the first point of contact for error reporting.

I have honed my follow-up, listening, and emotional intelligence skills which have enabled me to handle clients and users in whatever state they are in and act promptly when they need services offered by the organization.

Professional Experience

Web Developer and Graphics Designer,

Freelancing

2021 - present | Nairobi, Kenya

I am detail oriented and proactive thus working as a freelancer in designing responsive websites and graphics design in accordance with the changing technology of Web Development applications.

Information Technology Intern,

Eldoret Law Courts

05/2022 - 07/2022 | Eldoret, Kenya

Through serving as an IT Intern under the ICT Department, I have gained practical skills and hands-on experience in the following areas:

- Providing technical support to computer users on the use of computer hardware and software applications.
- Computer networking and configuration to support traffic, improve network security, and increase network stability.
- Installing and upgrading computer software and hardware components to ensure usability.
- PC hardware maintenance and troubleshooting techniques to solve software issues and replace damaged hardware.
- Collecting data, establishing facts, and drawing valid conclusions to solve technical and operational challenges in the scope of IT as reported by users.
- Installing and upgrading anti-virus software to ensure security at the user level.

Hotel Steward, Kongoni Camp Hotel

04/2019 - 08/2019 | Nanyuki, Kenya

Through working in the Hospitality Industry, I have gained experience in offering good customer service and discussing any issues with a wide variety of individuals and groups. I am equipped with social media management skills which entails creating and publishing content, interacting with users, and analyzing performance.

Skills

Technical aspects of IT Technology

Using computer hardware, computer software and networks to organize data and information thus spending less time searching for information. Providing support to computer users, making me the first point of contact for error reporting. Installing and configuring hardware and software components to ensure usability.

Keeping all systems and software up to the current release.

Managing, prioritizing any IT problems, and solving technical and operational challenges in the scope of IT as reported by users.

Microsoft Office Suite

Proficient in using Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Suite, for instance, developing new and complex Excel sheets to generate ICT equipment issuance data quickly reducing time from 14 days to 7. Using Microsoft Word to generate different formats in accordance with the need and importance, for efficient presentation of information.

Using Microsoft Teams to combine workplace chat, meetings, notes, and attachments thus enabling collaboration and communication between the users.

Web Development

I am skilled to work with the following frontend and backend web development languages; HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS and React in designing responsive websites in accordance with the changing technology of Web Development applications.

Graphic Design

Proficient in using Adobe Photoshop 2021. In designing I use the aesthetics of typography and the compositional arrangement of the text, ornamentation, and imagery to convey ideas, feelings, and attitudes beyond what language alone expresses.

Great Communication Skills

Through working as an IT Intern, I have gained communication skills from interpersonal interactions thus enabling me to have excellent command of English (both written and spoken). Ability to communicate in foreign language (German) and express myself simply and coherently.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information

Technlogy, *University of Eldoret* 2018 – 2022 | Eldoret, Kenya

Goethe Zertifikat B1,

udemy.com, Goethe Insitut-Nairobi 01/2023 – 03/2023

Certificate of Proficiency in Computer Applications, Kenya Institute of Management 04/2018 - 05/2018 | Nanyuki, Kenya

Goethe German Zertifikat A2,

Goethe Institut-Muenchen
06/2016 – 07/2016 | Munich, Germany

References

Wycliffe Ireri, *ICT Officer*, Eldoret Law Courts wyckieireri@gmail.com, +254703603017

Isabella Karani, *Teacher*, Inoro Secondary School isabkieb@yahoo.com., +254723549719

Cyrus Maina, *German Teacher*, Lanet Secondary School wairagu24@gmail.com, +254722452971